In this video we are going to discuss
best car insurance in
2026.  Yes, IRDA has officially
released its list.  So who has settled how many
claims basically
within 2024-25?  His figures have come out here.
And on that basis I will tell you the
latest claim settlement ratio.
Which companies should you consider?   I
will also show you their plans.  How do you
compare?  Plus if you
want to reduce your premium.  So, which are those
hidden add-ons that you should remove
and along with that,
what is the process of cashless and reimbursement on car
insurance, so please watch the entire video
here and
I have already given all the supporting links
in the description box.  So brother, first of all,
IRDA basically publishes this kind of
huge data here
every year and this time we have
put it inside Chat GPT.
Now first of all, you should understand ICR which we
call Incident Claim Ratio.
Its simple meaning is that how much payout a
company is giving here within the entire year i.e.
within the entire financial year.
How much is it settling the claim
and how much is it earning along with it.  So
see, if this is more than 100,
it means that the company is in loss here.
Above 50 to 100% it is
considered the ideal range.  So guys, first of all,
here the highest loss making is 100%, that is,
if we
see from our point of view as a consumer brother, then
they have settled the claim here, but the
company is going into loss.  So
if you look within the top three, you will
see government companies.  National
Insurance Company Limited, Oriental
Insurance Company Limited and Neo India.
Apart from this, you will find HDFC among the private players.  That
means,
if you want to choose a private company, then
you can shortlist HDFC.
Apart from this, in the range of 90 to 100% also
you can see many government
companies and in private there is SBI General
Reliance and you will get
to see similar companies and now you can also
see moderate ones, you will get to see Kotak Liberty Royal Sundaram
Tata AIG Navi Bajaj Futuch Shriram
and in less than 70 there is
God digit Chola Mandalam ICIC LB etc. which are the
general companies of Universal.
So first of all let's
talk about the types of car
insurance.  So you
can divide it into two categories.  There is a
third party, there is a comprehensive one.
Third party means this brother
is compulsory.  Without this you cannot take out the car or
drive it.  So
what is here does not protect your car.
But if you damage someone, he will
definitely protect him.  Plus there is a
fixed premium here.
As you can see in front of my screen.
Whether I take it from Kotak, National
Insurance or United India
Insurance.  Since then, the
third party premium for my car is ₹3416.
So whether you are buying from a private company or from
anywhere else, your
third party premium remains
flat.  It remains the same.  No matter
which insurance company you take it from.
Along with this, the rule is that
you should have a personal accidental cover of ₹15 lakh.
So here you can save money.
Yes, when you buy an insurance policy,
if there is
any personal
accidental cover already added with your credit card or debit card, then
you can easily save something like ₹300 to ₹350 on it.  Now brother, the
second plan is
comprehensive insurance.
Comprehensive means that
third party is covered in it.  Along with that,
if there is any damage to your vehicle, that is
also covered here.  In which there was theft
, accidental, fire.  So
all such things are covered.  So, basically, keeping in mind
commercial use and illegal
driving is
not applicable there.  Now first of all let us talk about the
two
plans that I told you about third party comprehensive, first of all if
you have to buy from anywhere in that.  First thing,
whenever most people redeem their Nike car here, they
buy it from the dealer only.
But brother, you should check one thing here
that what is the premium of what the dealer is offering you
and
here you can easily compare the premium of a new car on the online policy
website,
for an example,
suppose you want to check the insurance of a brand new car here,
I will give you the link
in the description box, so
here you will just enter your maker model number
etc., it will automatically tell you the
complete insurance information according to the car,
premium etc. here,
now let us talk about the fact that brother, there are
many insurance companies
but how will we know which is the
best insurance company?  So you can judge
any company here on the basis of three parameters.
One is your claim
settlement ratio which we call CSR.
This means that out of the number of claims received by a company in a year,
how many claims did it settle here.  The second is
Cashless Garage.  Where, suppose your
car breaks down, you do
not have to spend money from your pocket.  The money is
given directly to the mechanics and authorized garages
through the company.  So there you will
not have to spend money from your pocket.  So you will have to check
how many cashless garages of this company are there in my nearby area.
And the third factor is IDV
value which we call insured declared
value.  The higher it is, the
higher your premium will be.  If
you reduce this, the premium will be less.  So
what is the actual IDV value?  So,
if you want to find out the IDV value of your vehicle,
then I will provide you the link of a calculator
in the description box.
Just enter your state here.
In which year did you buy the car?
Here basically your maker is done.  Which
is basically the model number?  So look, if you enter these things then
automatically you
get an IDV value.  That means, the
amount that remains on your vehicle after depreciation can be
seen here.  This is the
maximum amount that the insurance
company provides you.  That means if the
car gets stolen tomorrow, the
insurance company will bear this maximum amount.  So,
when you compare the premium on the website of any insurance company,
you are given a slider of IDV.
So here every
insurance company gives you different
IDV value.  So always keep in mind that
you should decide the best IDV value for yourself here
so that if tomorrow the
vehicle here becomes a total loss, then the
insurance company will give you the maximum amount.  Along with this,
guys anywhere if you are
comparing insurance here.  Basically, suppose
after one year, here you are
asked for the percentage of no claim bonus.  Now what is this no claim
bonus etc.?  I
want to explain this to you in a simple way.  If
you have not made any claim here in the last 5 years
and if
you want to renew in the sixth year or
even want to shift from one company to another, then
you are given a discount of 50% on the
premium.  And
what's the best part?  If you are
switching companies, then the other company also
offers you the same NCB discount here.
So here you can see that even
if I go to Policy Bazaar,
I will be asked about NCB there also.
Suppose if I
compare my plan here on Ekko, then
NCB will ask me for it there also.  This
NCB percentage basically becomes
almost 50% after 5 years.  But
suppose your vehicle is only 2-3 years old
and if you have not made any claim here basically, then
you can see that
this slab five basically runs around 20% 25% 35%
and here an
advice is also always provided that
whenever you have a small claim of ₹1000 ₹2000, then
you should never make a claim
because you also have to calculate that
if I make a claim then how much of
my NCB am I going to lose here.
Now let us talk about the
many add-ons that are available in the car insurance policy.  There are
some add ons which are
quite good.  There are some that are
unnecessary that you should remove.
Now let me talk about must have add ons
if you have a shiny car.  If
your vehicle is not more than 5 years old, then
basically you should always take zero depreciation
cover.  We also call it bumper to
bumper cover.  So look,
you will always get the option of zero dump inside the add ons.
But this is provided only on new vehicles.
And one
thing to keep in mind is that whatever premium you are getting,
almost 70 to 80% of it will be
incremented here.  But
brother, what benefit will you get from this, that whenever you
go to make a claim, basically for almost all the
items made of plastic, rubber, glass parts, you will have to pay
50% from your pocket.  But now
because there is zero tap here, you will
not have to pay anything.  The only
disadvantage of this is that your premium
increases here.  Otherwise, if you have a shiny
car, make sure there should be zero deps here.
Apart from this, guys you
should check the invoice price cover which is
also called RTI, also called return to invoice.
So, if you have a very shiny
car which you have just bought from the showroom just
one year ago, then this cover should also be
added to you so that if the car gets stolen tomorrow, then ultimately the
insurance
company gives you the ex-showroom value of the same car.  Apart from this,
consumables cover should also be your add.
So there is brake oil, engine oil,
etc. You have to pay for it
from your pocket.  If consumables cover is your option,
you will not have to pay anything from your pocket.
Now if I talk about what
things you can remove here so that you
can save money.  Firstly,
you can save money through the personal accidental cover that I told you about,
if you already have it.
Apart from this, it is normally seen that when
you buy a new car here,
things like road sign assistant are also added.
So, if you do
not need it then you can definitely remove it
because mostly
you get
to see it as a benefit in the credit card also.  Apart from this, I
would like to tell you one thing here that whenever
you go to make an insurance claim here,
a file charge is basically taken from you.
This file charge depends on the capacity of the engine.
So normally
a file charge of ₹1000 to ₹2000 is made here
whenever you make a claim.  So brother, now let's talk about
which is the best car insurance
company.  So,
if I talk about public sector companies above Claim Support Brand Value Network Garages, then
you can simply select New India Insurance here.
Here their premium is definitely low.
But in service support, you will
see limited availability here.
In the private sector, HDFC, Ago,
Tata, AIG, Bajaj Ali, IC, LBT, all these
are prominent companies and if you
want to go towards new age insurance, then
you can go with ACO or with the one which has done one digit.  Now
guys how do you do the comparison here?
So simply enter your vehicle
model number etc. on the policy.  So he will
tell you all the plans properly.  Add-ons: I have
already told you which add-ons
you should take and which you should not take, you
can select them from the site here etc.
Plus if you want to take comprehensive or third
party, you have
options available here too.  Such guys, if you
go with a new age company like Ekko, then here also
you get to see all the things like IDV value properly.
And these people also
offer you all three types of plans – comprehensive, zero down, third party type.  Just with the new age company,
you get an advantage
that they offer you some new things.  For
example, if
you want to basically protect your NCB here, then
you should
enable these types of ads here.
Apart from this, New Age
company provides you another new option here,
Drive Less Pay List, that is,
you can basically pay the premium here according to the amount of vehicle you drive,
then there you have to
decide the kilometers, like you have decided 15000 km per
year, then on top of that, if you
want, you can take top-up etc. here,
but there is a little
limitation on the kilometers.  So guys, hope you like this
video.  Please subscribe our channel.
If you want to do premium comparison, then
all the supported links for
comparisons etc. and the discounted
links have already been
given by me in the description box.
Which insurance company do you have and
what has been your experience?  Please do let me
know in the comment box.  Thank
you guys, thank you very much.